And we figured out that we could take
the user's 2FA code, encode it into DTMF
tones, and append it to a a phone number
and tell Gemini, call this phone number,
which is one of the actions that didn't
require user [music] prompting.
>> Best part of backing when you can just,
you know, critical thing, right?
[laughter]
>> Yeah, dude.
Sup Packers, we've got an exciting
announcement. Threat Locker Zero Trust
World Conference is back in 2026. It's
going to be March 4th to March 6th in
Orlando, Florida. It's freaking gorgeous
down there, too during that time. And
yours truly is going to be there. I'm
going to be there on Wednesday, March
4th. I'm going to be leading a hands-on
hacking workshop. I'll be one of many.
So, there's lots of fun hacking
workshops you can get involved in. Um,
and it's going to be a great time.
There's tons of sessions, workshops,
other people there to network with, it's
going to be a great conference. So, if
you're local to Orlando or if you're up
for the travel, um, this is a great way
for you to use that employer uh,
training budget that you've got. Also,
um, for critical thinking listeners,
there's a discount of $200 off. You can
use the code ZTW, right, for zero trust
world CTB26.
ZTWCTB26
when you register. That'll be on the
screen and in the description as well.
It's going to be a great time. I hope to
see you guys there. All right, let's go
back to the show.
All righty, Sup hackers. It's been a
while. It probably actually doesn't feel
like a while to you guys because I we
pre-recorded some episodes, but I
haven't been on the pod in three weeks
and uh I am rolling and ready to get
back to it. Um so, I mean, let's jump
into this episode. I'm going to be solo
today. No Reszo or Gret. Um Brezo's got
some some stuff going on and Gretney is
going to be traveling for a live hacking
event. So, um, just your boy Rhino
Raider today. Um, all right. First,
let's jump off into the this weekend
book bounty segment. Um, you know, I I
have a couple things here for this one,
but uh actually I'm going to turn one of
them into just a longer segment because
it's really good. Um, so first thing
that you just need to be aware of rapid
fire is Integrity launched a new program
called AS Watson. This is a big like
massive scope family, you know, of of
companies sort of situation here. And
the bounties are quite good. Um, we're
looking at 4 to 7K uh criticals um highs
in 1.2 to four. Um, and a massive scope.
So, watch your tier levels for sure. I
mean, obviously they go down to quite
low uh for tier five or whatever. Um,
but if you're hacking on the main scope,
uh, this is a nice fresh new program you
can take a look at for a u a company
that is very big in in Asia, the AS
Watson Group. So, check that out. Um, so
that's where I'm I'm actually done with
the TWIB and now we're going to go into
act the actual main content for the
episode. Got a lot of news, but I'm also
going to throw in some some fun tidbits
for you guys. Uh we're going to talk a
little bit about um I guess sort of a
realization that I had about sea surf
which I feel like I should have known
but didn't really hit. And then at the
end we're going to talk a little bit
about um crossconsumer attacks which is
something that Fron and I uh have been
working a little bit on in the um
critical thinkers research guild from a
while back. Um so we're going to cover
that as well. Okay. So, first up though
before we jump into those things is the
Yes, We Hack 2026 report. Um, so I I try
to go through each one of these like bug
bounty program or platform reports
whenever they come out and grab the
useful tidbits for you guys. And not
going to lie, Yes, We Hack is putting
out some pretty sick content for all
this. So, um, actually, let me go ahead
and expand my screen here. Um, I'm going
to give you guys a lot of the data out
of this report, but I would also
recommend you go check it out. We're
going to we're going to link it in the
description. Uh first they they're
showing they're giving more data on how
hunters are actively using uh AI. This
is an N is N of 245. So this is 245
hackers surveyed for this. Um and most
hackers are using AI for improved report
clarity and structure which I don't know
if it's getting them more clarity or not
because I've seen some really crap AI
generated reports lately. I still don't
use AI to generate my reports. Um, I
help it I I have it help sometimes when
I I'm doing something particularly
complex, but I write all of my reports
by hand typically. Uh, and that I find
that that gets them accepted more more
quickly. Um, 32% are using it to create
think creatively and and thanks to the
AI automation and 31% are using it to
find more bugs, more complex and subtle
bugs. Um, I've had a lot of success in
the past couple weeks with using o opus
4.6 to find some very, very deep um,
client side bugs that I wouldn't have
found. Um, so I definitely recommend you
guys use something like JX Scout to get
the JavaScript files down and then throw
it into cloud code and just have it go
ham because it does a very good job of
analyzing client side routes, um, query
parameter parsing, hash parsing, uh,
post message listeners, all sorts of
things. So definitely recommend you you
take a look at that. Um
and uh we see 69% are using AI for
learning and documentation, 51% for
drafting reports, 40 for uh payload
generation, um 38 for code review and
vulnerability analysis. Payload
generation I think is a big one um for
me. Uh 26% for recon and 23% for um
escalating bones. 9% are not using AI.
So um I mean we we're seeing a lot of
rapid adoption here. I would definitely
recommend you join this 40% that's using
it for payload generation and 38% for
code review and vulnerability analysis.
It is extremely extremely good. Um and
that's coming from like a a pretty
experienced client side hacker. It is
amazing. So definitely uh build out your
own workflow for that. All right. Next
one was on page 44 um that I thought was
interesting. Uh of the hunters surveyed,
44% have been hacking for four to or 3
to four years or 3 to 5 years. Um which
is not as long as expected to be honest.
Um so that's pretty encouraging. And 38%
of hunters are full-time hunters on Yes,
We Hack, which is kind of crazy. 62% are
doing it uh in addition to some other
role. Um so it's good to see the
full-time hunters growing a little bit.
I like that. Uh, and I was surprised to
see that number be so high. Um, we're
also seeing the best ways to improve
your hacking skills uh are as YouTube
videos. You know, hey, maybe you're
watching this on YouTube. Uh, yes, we
hack dojo and uh, uh, oh, okay. So,
actually, it's like hands-on practice
with bug bounty platforms first. Um, and
then we're also seeing YouTube videos,
yes, we hack dojo, online educational
platforms, and uh, blog posts and
writeups, which I totally agree with.
Um, we've also seen a 520% increase in
collaboration reports on Yes We Hack,
which is sick. Um, so lots of
collaboration going on. And the top
tools in the toolkit are Burpsweet, FUF,
and HBX, which makes sense.
Unfortunately, we're only seeing Kaido
down here at 18% adoption uh versus 91%
on Burpuite. So, um, seems like in the
Yes, We Hack world, Kaido is is uh only
at 18%, but um, a lot of the top hunters
I know are using Kaido. So, uh,
surprising, but yeah, I guess you know,
old habits die hard. Um, yeah, also I
wanted to to call out this on page 55.
There are top performing hunters by C.WE
types. And I know, okay, guys, we're
getting into a little bit of meta here,
okay? But like there are some recon boys
out there that will not talk about what
they do at all. Um, and this guy, this
this little graph here gives us a little
bit a peak into what exactly they might
be doing. Go Diego has uh you know
denied my request to come on the pod
multiple times. Uh and he is coming in
as the top hacker for cash poisoning. So
that could be a part of his his secret
methodology. And doxing of course
unsurprisingly is coming in with um
subdomain takeovers. So um cash
poisoning and subdomain takeovers are
probably what are making these guys top
of the leaderboard right now. Um which
is really cool to see. They also
included a long section on various
hackers expertise. So you know Chakal's
methodology for stored XSS. Um there's
one for uh information disclosure. Um
IDORE etc. So if you're looking to know
like what the methodology is for these
top hackers um this is a good place to
find it. Um overall I thought this
report was really awesome. They talked
about the live hacking events. They
talked about um the assessment of you
know vulnerabilities that people are
finding. um they're sharing methodology
and they even also highlight some of the
research. Let's see if I can find it.
Yeah, some of my favorite research that
came out this year, exploiting syntax
confusions in the wild by Alex Broomman.
So, um definitely worth a read, uh high
quality, um bug bounting platform
report. Okay, so uh we went through
that. Let's jump now over to what I was
going to talk about with regards to
curves. Okay, so I was exploiting a bug
the other day [clears throat] and I was
like, "Okay, you know, I've got this
curf. Um,
it it does something to the victim's
account that it would be more helpful if
I could do it multiple times." Um, and I
was like, "Ah man, I'm going to have to
like pop up a new tab and like distract
the user while I'm like redirecting and
stuff like that." And then I realized,
you know, hey, even though this has
X-Frame options set to deny,
it doesn't matter.
and and same site cookies are are none
for this which was what we wanted. So
it's still sending you know the cookies
into the iframe. Um it's just not going
to be able to show the result but it
doesn't matter for Caesar because it's a
state changing thing. So you know one of
what I ended up doing was just creating
a bunch of iframes with this state
changing you know action and all of them
you know failed to load because xframe
options was denied but it doesn't matter
because the cookies are sent and the
request is processed server side. So I
was just able to like like send a bunch
of uh you know curfs at the same time
and I don't know why I hadn't really
wrapped my head around it but like
x-frame options doesn't get processed
obviously until the response is
processed and by that point the curf has
already had its effect. So just like
make sure I know it gets tricky nowadays
with like iframes and like fetch
requests and stuff like that and what
cookies are going to be sent with same
site and and that sort of thing but um
really the for CS surf you know the
thing you need to be checking is does it
have the same site cookies in place
right you don't really have to think
about oh is it ifraable or not ifraable
um uh in this situation I had to do it
by an iframe versus fetch but um just
keep that in mind uh they that you know
x-frame options is not doesn't prevent
you from executing curves inside of an
iframe. Um, just a thought there. Um,
all right. Up next is a write up by uh
our own um Mon. And this was a collab
between Mon Reszo, me and Lupin at a
live hacking event um in Tokyo. And this
was one a very fun creative bug that we
all did together. And it it was released
on Starstrike.ai's
blog, which is um Boss Factor and
Monke's new AI consulting firm. Um, so
this is such a fun bug I wanted to tell
you guys about it. Um, he does a a great
introduction into like the anatomy of a
data excfiltration vulnerability in
modern uh AI environments. But the TLDDR
of the situation is, you know, we've got
some um some way to deliver the payload.
You get the actual data that you need
and then you Xfill that. Right? So
there's kind of those three components
that you need. So, the delivery
component for this exploit was a um
intent URI that you can utilize inside
of uh the Gemini app, uh which would
allow you to preload a query into the
victim's Gemini. Um, and because it
loads so quickly, you can actually use
tapjacking for this. So, you know, you
create an app, they're tapping, you
know, hey, tap this button five times,
they tap it one, two, three, right? And
then on the third, you trigger the
intent swap and preload the prompt in.
And then by the time they're done
tapping, you know, their finger is right
on the send button for Gemini and it
triggers the the exploit. So it's kind
of like clickjacking. It's not the most
optimal method and we actually figured
out a way to um you know deliver this
payload differently afterwards, but um
it tapjacking is an interesting term
that you we don't talk about a ton. So
uh just wanted to highlight that for
y'all is that that is a way to get your
payload in in a worst case scenario. Um
so anyway, we got the payload in. We
said, "Hey, Gemini, you know, because it
has access to the user's data, um their
their messages and stuff like that on an
on the Android device, um we could say,
hey, grab the 2FA code from the user's
message, and now we got to get it out,
right?" So, that's the exfiltration
piece. Um, and we actually did this via
DTMF tones, [gasps and laughter] which
is uh some OG hacker right here,
which um that that's those tones you
hear when you call a number and it goes,
you know, and it's like, you know,
putting in these specific numbers via
frequencies, right? Um, so what we found
is that if you put the um um, you know,
I believe it was a hashtag or maybe it
was a semicolon. it's a semicolon after
the um after the number, you know, you
can get it to automatically play these
DTMF tones. And we figured out that we
could take the user's 2FA code, encode
it into DTMF tones and append it to a a
phone number and tell Gemini called this
phone number, which is one of the
actions that didn't require user
prompting. Right? So, with that one tap
on the tapjack, it would read the
messages, grab the 2FA code, and then
call us. And we had like the sick PC
video where we had like another phone
sitting right next to it and you know
we'd pick up the phone and it would go
or whatever you know the the the DTMF
tone and then you would see the the 2FA
code pop up on the attacker's phone
because it was it was you know
processing the the uh DTMF tones. So
that is a good way to let me say that is
a way [laughter] to excfiltrate data in
these sort of environments. Um, and I
was really proud of the team for coming
up with that really creative solution.
Um, and yeah, Google liked it. So, we we
got a bounty and we got um 1337 bonus uh
for the most creative vulnerability of
that live hacking event. So, that was a
blast.
Um, all right. Up next is
some some news that we kind of have to
cover that's a little bit little bit
tricky. um which is
Hacker 1 recently and I I'll give a
shout out to uh W2W here who tweeted
this out. Um both Spotify and the Hacker
1 program um decreased their bounties
pretty substantially lately. This is not
something we like to see, especially
from a platform. Um and I've reached out
to Hacker 1 to get a comment on this.
Uh, unfortunately this happened just
super recently and we're kind of
recording this episode last minute
anyway. So I haven't had the opportunity
to get Hacker One to give us a comment
on that. But we're going to cover that
comment on the next episode um because I
think they will get back to us uh about
it. But um you know here I am. I'm
wearing a Hacker 1 shirt. If you can't
see I'm wearing a Hacker 1 uh t-shirt.
Um this is not great to see but you know
Hacker 1 is still paying good bounties
here. you know, they're paying 1,500 for
a medium, 7k for a high, 15k for a crit.
Um, I I am confused by their their
decision to decrease their bounties. So,
uh, I guess we'll see how they respond
to that next time. Um, but I think the
general sentiment is that they are um
doing that in alignment with other book
money programs and to which the hacker
response is, well, you need to be
setting the the tone, right? Not
following, right? Um, so we'll see what
Hacker 1's response to that is. Also, in
in the PR in the PR hit that H1 has been
taking right now, um, there's also some
people that have been highlighting
section 3.1 of Hacker 1's general terms
and conditions, which says, and I quote,
"Hacker 1 may use confidential
information to develop andor improve its
services. For example, identify trends
and train AI models, provided such use
does not result in disclosure of
confidential information to unauthorized
third parties." Now, a lot of people are
interpreting this to mean, you know,
hey, they're taking our data, they're
training like, you know, the super
hacker AI. Um, I I have spoken with some
Hacker One representatives in the past
that have claimed that that is not the
case. Um, and there's no project under
underway for that. Um, but there is
something in the terms and conditions
here. Um, my intuition is that that this
is being used, you know, in context with
HI, which is Hacker 1's AI system, which
helps write reports and deal with that
sort of thing. Um, and this is sort of
like a catch-all statement. Um, but a
lot of hackers are sort of dismayed by
that and don't want their confidential
information being used um, with AI
models. So, I also reached out to Hacker
One to get a comment on that and we'll
see what they say. Um, but these uh,
terms and conditions have been in in
effect since uh, July 20th of 24. So,
it's been a while at this point. Uh, and
I'm not sure why it's just coming back
up into the public eye, but I did want
to address it for you all um, in full
transparency,
and I will let you know when we hear
back more from Hacker One about that.
All right. Uh, up next is, uh, I just
wanted to give a shout a little bit
here. Um, when you're done with today's
episode of Critical Thinking, this is
going to be a short episode. Uh we I got
a lot going on right now, but um when
you're done with this episode, I
recommend you go over to Turbo 7 uh URB0
YouTube channel and watch research
review number -2, rce and Google's AI
code editor, anti-gravity by Sudi. So
this is one of the best hackers I know
who is unfortunately also like from my
little town that I live in. So, I I like
can't even claim to be the best hacker
in my little town, you know, is uh is
this guy Turbo, and he's amazing. Um,
and he's doing a review of some research
and giving his comments, and this guy is
just so full of passion for hacking.
Like, you guys know me, I'm full of
passion for hacking. He is full of
passion for hacking. Okay. Um, and he's
going to be releasing some videos, it
seems, uh, doing research reviews, uh,
and just kind of giving his thoughts.
And he actually does some research
reviews for us at Critical Thinking as
well. um applications into the research
lab. So um he does a great job with this
and he he's very very smart. So if you
want to go hear his um research reviews,
you can find that on his YouTube
channel. We'll link that in the
description. So if you're looking for a
little bit of extra content to fill in
where CTB is is lacking this week, then
uh Turbo's got you covered. All right.
Um last but not least, I did want to
talk to you guys a little bit about some
um research that I think we mentioned on
the pod a while back that Fron and I
were kind of cooking on. um a while
back. Um so let me take a drink of my
water real quick.
Okay, let's get to that. So this is
something that we are sort of branding
crossconsumer attacks [snorts] and I'm
hoping that we'll get a write up on the
um on the critical thinking research lab
soon on these types of attacks. We've
pocked them in several areas and we've
also seen them, you know, out in the
community pretty often. Um, and what
these are are essentially scenarios
where a target company is utilizing a
third party to do something like um,
load JavaScript files, documentation,
you know, whatever it is, right? Um,
support apps or whatever. and they've
got part of their domain pointed at this
third party and they've got um uh or
maybe like a path even on their main
domain pointed at this third party,
right? Um and what you can do is you can
sign up for that third party yourself
and create your own tenant or whatever
and then host content on your tenant,
right? Let's call it like an SVG file or
an HTML file or whatever, right? and
then um take that URL that is used to
access your own content and try to
access it on the target. Right? So the
scenario that we're we're talking about
here is you know you've got some website
and maybe like it's like /docs1356814
you know test.html HTML or whatever and
you know that ID just looks like an
idor, right? And um and so you know if
you can access your uploaded content to
this third party on your targets domain
then you may be able to induce things
like XSS. Um we've seen this many times.
It's very hard to to fix because for the
third party like uh you know these URLs
are supposed to be public but only under
your domain, right? So it's kind of
tricky. you know, you get into those
situations where it's like, okay, well,
they're accessing, you know, public
content or whatever. Um, so it's it's
tricky. You know, a lot of a lot of
third-party providers are are pretty
vulnerable to this. Um, so just keep
that in mind as an attack vector. I know
that hacking third parties is a little
bit, you know, weird sometimes or
whatever. Um, but we've seen this
accepted quite often and, you know,
impact is king nowadays. So, just make
sure you're proving impact. So, let me
give you a couple tips for that. Uh
obviously checkout URLs in the path.
Sometimes there's also slugs in the
path. You know instead of you know
slashgoogle you put in /rinerator and
now it's got you know rerators you know
uploaded content there. Um look for file
uploads right? So you were looking for
SVG files we're looking for HTML files.
Even hosting.js files can there can help
you you know bypass um CSP or something
like that. Um so keep that in mind. Um
you can also you know sometimes they
have these hosts as like holes in their
CSP in general um which can help for you
know data expiltration or um XSS of
course and then um one other area that
I've seen this work or two other areas
is sometimes these like paths that you
have um sort of dedicated from the main
domain the main victim domain to this
third party they will accept parameters
that will allow you to override what
host the content is related to. So just
kind of run GA, you know, do some Google
dorking on that sort of path pattern and
see if there's any parameters that pop
up and read the documentation for the
third party a lot um to understand if
there's any debug parameters that will
allow you to say hey I know that this is
on you know Google's domain or whatever
but instead uh you know let's let's go
ahead and point it to rhinerators and
then that will allow you to override. So
that's an interesting technique. Um, and
then last but not least, sometimes there
are specific tokens for this. So rather
than just an ID in the URL or whatever,
they like sign a URL or they'll like
generate a JWT token or something like
that which will allow you to access that
restricted content. Um, check for the
scenarios where the third party is
downloading files, not like PDF files
and stuff like that, not just like
generating HTML pages or whatever. Um,
and sometimes those signed URLs or those
um, uh, specific um, patterns of
accessing it via a token will allow you
to uh, access your data on a different
customer's site which can induce XSS.
So, uh, keep a lookout for those sort of
attacks. We're calling those
crossconsumer attacks. Uh, I think it
fits the the concept pretty well and u,
we've seen them quite often around. So,
uh, keep it keep your eye out and yeah,
drop something in the CTB Discord if you
guys find one. Uh, I would like to know
how how, uh, you know, common they are
around and hear about any success
stories you guys might have with that.
All right. Um, that's about it. That's
all I've got for you guys today. Go
watch that content by Turbo and uh, I'll
see you guys next week. Peace.
And that's a wrap on this episode of
Critical Thinking. Thanks so much for
watching to the end, y'all. If you want
more critical thinking content,
>> [music]
>> uh, or if you want to support the show,
head over to ctbb.show/isord.
You can hop in the community. There's
lots of great highlevel hacking
discussion happening there on top of
master classes, [music] hackalongs,
exclusive content, and a full-time
hunters guild. If you're a full-time
hunter, [music] it's a great time. Trust
me. All right, I'll see you there.